this is not my first time this is like
all i do
i can't edit videos but i can i can go
live and do one
one take so i really and i can have
conversations with people
so yeah yeah yeah well that is my game b
this is exactly how i'm bringing it into
the world so
do you want to do you want to just in
case someone is watching this and it is
a little bit more like a podcast just
give a little brief rundown of what we a
pen is i might have said it wrong but
what your project is part of my project
oh okay
okay um i in a way
it's probably best to start off with a
little bit about
who i am and and my life
just a little bit um i'm an artist
visual artist so um and i
kind of wrote this down to where i
wouldn't forget
um as as an artist it's my
responsibility to assess complex
subject matter and try to make sense of
whatever i choose to create
through completing an actionable project
i.e painting drawing sculpture
whatever it is i choose to create
so uh naturally i gravitated
and became consumed with a creative
process i call participate of art
now what is participative art is
basically
unfinished pieces of artwork i place
wherever
i can show
the patrons or the or the viewers
complete the artwork by following my
instructions back in the day
you know after i graduated from fashion
college i went to went to school to make
clothes
and um shortly after that
uh acquired a patent for some gene that
i
created around 2002 um
but it was around this time when i was
working with and
uh creating this art form something i
thought i'd never seen before because
the most important aspect of
participative art
is not focused on my expression in fact
the more i take
me out of the creative process
the more
it interested me it interested the
public because it was all about
their expressions not not mine
and uh let's see
basically in retrospect this was my way
of examining
and learning how to heal our ancestry
all the way up to us i mean this is just
me me now looking back and and kind of
examining why
i came up with this concept it was um
it was to heal this ancestry on up to us
uh from being damaged through the
process of civilization
creation i mean all of these things
happening from
century on up to us now
has created damaged people because we
aren't
exactly who we should be you know
what you strive to do i i know growing
up
um throughout school um
not knowing that i was autistic was
extremely difficult
you know um even though
uh the whole process of
socializing and making friends and
even the educational system of actually
learning
was extremely difficult but within that
process
um i started to see
and understand that
[Applause]
things were happening outside myself
things were
you know my life was evolving towards
some purpose towards some
goal whatever that was i
i could feel it i did i couldn't express
or understand exactly
where i was headed but i
i can remember one time i'm thinking
myself
wow uh i don't think i have to study
i mean i did but i didn't think i had to
because i felt like
no matter what i did
i was propelling i would i would pass
tests that i didn't necessarily study
for
and i would uh eventually prepare to
graduate and go on to fashion college
and
all these other things and i had the
sense that
it was something that i really i wasn't
in control
something else was propelling me to do
these other things
and um i don't know if you're
familiar with uh the law of attraction
familiar with it yeah yeah don't like it
because it's full of toxic positivity
but i also find it works like i believe
in it i think it's real
and i don't think we do it right in any
way shape or form i think
that okay yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah cause
um
uh it's it's crazy because
uh i truly felt like
i was living the principles i was living
out the principles of
the law of attraction without really
even hearing
the term before i heard the term i felt
like
this i was being attracted to whatever
my life's purpose was whatever it was i
was supposed to be doing whatever
yeah so uh
yeah yeah that's that's kind of like
that my early
stage in life
and uh get i'll get to
basically about five years ago around
the time i met my wife
uh and she's from she's from korea she's
korea
but and she was actually living here in
guatemala at the time
around five years ago um
i had an idea you know just an idea just
because i i transitioned from the
artwork
to thinking more so of like okay
i am i'm creative enough
uh let's see if i can create an
application a tech
you know a mobile application that has
some of the principles of what i'm
creating in my
art yeah i had no
concept of where it was going or how i
was going to make it or
i have no tech background whatsoever
so you know i have this idea i come to
guatemala
and i speak to a friend of my wife or
her name is
uh but
the guy i speak to he's a business owner
here in guatemala
and still is still owns the same bar
uh i told him about my idea
and he was like oh george this sounds
that sounds cool i have some ideas
myself maybe we can
talk about it at the mo some other time
like okay you know nothing ever happened
on that trip
but um me and my parents
once i went back home my second trip
back to guatemala
my parents came with me and before we
left
hate him gave me a call and was like you
remember the guy you told your
idea to he would like to give you ten
thousand dollars
to help you out with that concept i was
like really
i knew i was on the right track even
though i had
nothing really fleshed out
i wasn't really ready but
i know i was on the right track because
when i
received the patent for my jeans the
same thing kind of happened when people
heard and saw the jeans they were
willing to give money and that's always
a good indicator that
especially from other people other than
your family and friends
that kind of give you confirmation that
what you're doing
is is okay um
[Music]
keep going so let's bring spring
forward from there about another
two about another two or three years and
we're living
and traveling the world now something
i've always wanted to do
and and put out into the universe that i
wanted to do now of i
think i've lived now since then until
now i've lived in about
nine countries um
but i guess this was a couple of years
ago or
two or three years we were living in
yangon myanmar now i never heard
of yangon before um
i i heard of burma but i didn't know
about yangon
you know so this is like a whole new
world that
you know totally opened up to me
um but
here's a story that i always think about
when i think about yanga
this is around the time when me and
hayden
were pretty much we had written down
the the principles and and fleshed out
the concept
for what happens at the time is what i
called it
um thanks to facebook it's no longer
what happens you can you can imagine why
um they it's as soon as well
spring forward a little bit past the
story i was going to tell you but
basically after i took the name to the
lawyer the lawyers basically
and he submitted it
for a trademark he came back and said
facebook
you know it says it's too close to what
what's that basically
so you have to change the name which is
a good thing because now
supporters have said purchase a lot
closer to your vision
we happen is a lot better okay
go back to yangon when i when we first
wrote down all the i mean we were pretty
it was
pretty stringent process of
getting my ideas out of my head onto
paper
once once we i was able to do that
i was beginning to start practicing not
only with my wife and
our friends but people in the
neighborhood and there happened to be
a business guy who lived
in our apartment complex and i had told
him about the content once before
but he didn't have enough time to really
delve into
the way he wanted to so he caught me
outside
him and his friend called me outside one
day and said george we have
some time you want to tell us about this
concept of yours
we you know we want to press you a bit
on on how you're going to make this
thing happen
like okay sure so i go up there
and his friend kind of sits to the side
and just kind of nods and
listens as as my neighbor
starts grilling me you know and this is
my first time to really be grilled on
the concept that
i've been just i'm pretty much finished
on paper
is there still some things missing
to make a long story short um
they could have said anything to me you
know oh george that's a
wonderful idea you know hopefully you do
something with it
um oh oh you know maybe it'll work maybe
maybe not but thank you
that didn't happen it was something that
pretty much solidified and confirmed in
me that
you know this was the path that i was
supposed to be taking
taking uh his friend
at the end of our discussion or towards
the end of our discussion said george
you are not leaving this apartment
until we get your autograph and i'm like
what
he's like yeah you're not leaving until
we get your autograph i'm like
what are you what are you talking about
he was like
a lot of what you said makes sense
especially your udi concept now
what was my udi concept i had heard
about ubi
it had been a long-standing project that
people
from all over the world they would start
in in small
groups and you know they would
experiment with
over time
i just changed one word to udi universal
data income
because i just felt like it was
something that was
a lot more achievable as opposed to
something that would have to go
through a ubi which is government based
it would have to be supply
finance i mean everything would have to
basically
that was the only way most people could
see financing such a large project
for to be able to pay everyone
an income no matter how large that
income
was the only source could be a
government
so to speak but i thought about it and
was like
well what about all the data
that we use every day but don't get
anything for
you know it's a resource now i mean this
was before
uh they were saying that you know data
is the new oil and all this other stuff
but it just made sense that
a resource that
we all produce no matter who you are in
the world as long as you're
using some form of electronic device
we all produce it we never run out of it
until you pass on and even then
you still could produce data there are
still ways that that could happen
uh this is this could be uh
this could be a pathway towards
creating something similar to a ubi
was my was my thinking so
uh they were like yeah that that makes
sense and it's a win-win for everyone
and i was like yeah you know i don't see
anything stopping that from happening
the only thing stopping it from
happening is us you know
why can't we do that why can't we come
together and make this thing happen
you know that was the next phase of
basically
trying to figure out okay
how old were you going to build a
movement
that would
that people could understand that
weren't tech people
and to get the thing rolling or the ball
rolling basically
so yeah um essentially that's the
that's the beginning of we happen
and um i just continued that that
process
of talking to whoever was willing to
listen
and um uh
i think the the next phase of my
evolution was
uh we were living in savannah
savannah kent laos at the time
and for whatever reason
the message that i posted on facebook
kind of exploded and
it touched the nerve with um a group i
had never heard of before
which was the venus project people
um i to me i hadn't i'd never heard of
him but it was
scary because it seemed like for
a whole week i was deluged with messages
and um people
wanting me to be some type of leader
and all these other things i mean it was
just it was a blur that whole week was a
blur
um but out of that came a lawyer who
wanted to work with me and
a core team of people around the world
who um resonated with the message
and a lot of those people are still with
me some people
were a little
how could i say
didn't really see or understand that
this was something that had to be done
as a collective
as opposed to something we could force
and push
some people had to fall to the wayside
and and
now it's more so um
the people that are joining and and i'm
attracting
uh there seems to be no
um nothing has to be forced no
no one is um leaving because
to be honest with you a lot of people
who are on my chat room a lot of people
in the we happen group page
uh i don't ask any i don't ask them to
do anything other than to spread the
word
nothing more nothing less you know i
don't i'm so
um but getting still they still
stay they and and i get messages all the
time
from people outside of the group that
i've never
talked to or heard of before they'll
they'll contact me and say george we see
what you're doing
we encourage you we we you know and it's
great
we're watching continue
so um that's that's a great thing too
so um yeah yeah that's where i'm at now
and my
uh i think the biggest
uh hurdle or no i wouldn't say hurdle
but
uh detractor um
critic that i've had was my wife
you know yeah now
you you have to you have to imagine
within the five-year period that we've
been together this has
been all that i've been consumed this is
like
i'm i'm obsessed i i
couldn't nor wanted to do anything else
including work
so i understand her position
you know and and wondering if this thing
is ever going to happen
or you know so it was just yesterday
that i told her about our meeting
and well she knew about it but
i was i was just practicing with her on
the things that i would discuss with you
about
and by the end of
my telling her and she's and usually
she's like
i don't i'm not interested in hearing
about we have to you know i mean
she usually kind of pushes me away but
uh today or yesterday she was like
by the end of um
listening to what i had to say she was
like
that's it you're on the right track now
i mean what you
what you said to me send it to me
because
i want to make sure that i write it down
and we un
and so the people that we speak to we
have a group of
um economists and social activists in
seoul south korea that are interested in
meeting up she wants to make sure that
she writes it
can you know make sure that it's clear
and we can translate that to them once
we get back to soap
or for whoever wants to you know
understand the concept she was like
if when you explain it like that
then yeah this you're on the right track
and i understand exactly where you're
headed you know
and i'm like yeah you know i'm i'm
basically ready
so uh but
it i often tell people what we're doing
is multi-dimensional
and everything um most of what
we'll talk about today is all connected
that's what makes it so complex for most
people to understand but
someone with my type of mind make is i'm
kind of uniquely qualified to not only
understand the fourth industrial
revolution
but the pathways towards getting
to the solutions and it can only be done
collectively and
um yeah yeah we'll we'll just
stop there and and see if you have any
questions
so far you know i got questions
i love it though i love power i also
it's funny because how your story does
not parallel mine
is that it does parallel mine that what
your wife said it's like i don't want to
hear about it anymore and that's
very much like i have a project i'm safe
in the world it's like
all i want to do is talk about it and
the regular world is like no you're not
no and so people aren't throwing money
at me but that is still
my underlying guide of like um following
the universe
following what what i don't follow is
the law of attraction because it's been
so co-opted by
by um the talk of positivity but like
this is happening in its right time
so i get frustrated further along and
people aren't
blocking to me at the same time whenever
anyone does i'm like i don't know how to
work with people like i don't because i
can only have video chat so i'm like how
do you do if you can't have emails if
you can't do that
and so i'm working through it with your
numbers but for your project
um i did you would listen to a bit of
our together tech roundtable yeah or
brought up some of the questions yeah
so with a lot of the other data projects
that are out there
they're the opposite like it's like you
control your own data but you keep it
behind a paywall like you keep it behind
right so you have full access to it but
we don't have our collective data which
is a problem because then we can't do
things with it it's like you have your
data
but their data kind of only works with
other people's data
so facebook and google of course have
our data and
other tech as well and they sell it to
people that's why they're billionaires
that's why they're growing faster than
any other company
exactly there are billions of us like
facebook only makes
ten dollars a year off of each of us but
that equals up to hundreds of billions
of dollars not per year
how do we get a ubi like thing
out of that without either so this is my
um is i want i think our data is both
very cheap
and priceless i want the priceless part
the cheap part doesn't counteract that
though like it's like we can't pay you
for your data from facebook or from who
facebook charges
and get you a living wage that you can
live off of
and encourage you to use your data for
the greater good
and your greater good and so yeah i'll
let you speak to that
yeah yeah um that's why it's extremely
important
because like you
language is ex even more
difficult for me back in the day when i
when i was younger
um when i could barely speak now
i've gotten a lot better but when it
comes to
explaining complex situations like this
it's easier for me to use video and
other media
to explain exactly where we're headed
because a lot of people are basically
saying the same thing
for thinking about the same processes
that
that we're talking about um
in ways that are a lot more
understandable i sent you the video of
jaren lanier did you did you
watch you said you've seen that one
right i've seen it yeah but i didn't
re-watch it because but
i haven't seen some of this yeah he he
explains
the concept of a mid a mediator of indi
individual data and you know this
this guy uh of course he coined the
phrase um
virtual reality he's he's a tech guy but
he's also an opponent he
i mean he hates the fact that we're not
getting paid for our data and trying to
figure out ways of making that happen
so he gets the tech side
more so than anybody any layman
he says that and i i'm i'm
i have no doubt that
facebook is making a lot more money off
of us individually
than they say why is that
um i think because
of course they don't want people to know
how much money they're making into
individually they want to keep that
as low as possible um of course
they're making well their primary source
just like with all these tech giants
their primary source of
revenue is advertising
but that's just one that's just one
caveat that's just one
avenue there's a whole new industry
or there's a whole other industry of
data agents that are selling our data
to corporations and industries
over and over again and i believe
facebook's doing the same thing
you know they're basically just just an
agent for our data but taking in
all the all the revenue like and that's
sharing
um
the other important thing to
to remember when talking about we happen
it is
not just uh technology based
the most important thing and i have to
stress this every time i talk to someone
the most important
aspect of what i do right now is what
we're doing
building relationships talking to each
other
you know it was extremely difficult for
me starting out
but now it gets easier the more you do
it obviously
um but yeah that has to be done because
it's
it's symbiotic with the mobile
application and the technology behind
the holochain and the
distributed ledger all this stuff that i
had to learn
that's being you know uh created now
that uh people said yeah this this
you know your data can be collected it
can
everything that we envision can be done
it's just a matter of creating the
prototype and making it happen but
like i said on the opposite side there
has to be
a social movement um
able to connect with that data or able
to
use the platform in order to to grow it
um and uh the the great thing about what
i'm talking about too
is i it's great and it's kind of uh
it's it's freeing for me
to not be able to have all the answers
um
i truly believe that the answers will
come through
um the dialogues that we have regardless
of whether you have
technology or not or technology
knowledge or not
along with those collective discussions
we'll have
and they don't have to be had with the
politicians
the tech uh people
um the environmentalists i mean every
sector
that you could possibly imagine has to
have
a seat at the table in order to really
build the pat pathways towards the
solutions
that even we want to envision you know
so
it's going to take a a collaborative
effort to do that
and like i say i i've got a
layman's uh knowledge of
technology but
from what i understand everything that i
pretty much laid out
can be done and there's a lot more money
out there
to be had than you know that the tech
companies
don't want us to know you know exactly
how they're
how they're doing that so um
let's see uh
i thought there was something so from
understanding the idea is that just
there is more money out there
more money yeah yeah yeah i mean do you
think that's enough to like is it enough
for us each to make 50 bucks a month or
is it enough for us to actually live off
of
as it is right now like if we could
somehow funnel
facebook our data from facebook and
google to this
central thing if we could do that
tomorrow how much money do you think we
could have
in an actual currency ubi type thing
with our data i know you're saying it's
going to emerge we'll see what that
exactly is
but you have an inkling yeah because it
would be around that's the
one probably one of the main questions
people ask
me is how much money do you think we
could
possibly make well um
i i just i just have to guesstimate like
anyone else until you actually
start to the prototyping and get enough
people
on there to to start really
doing the numbers on on this
but just looking at what's
what's happening now realistically
speaking
facebook has a little over two billion
members something like this
uh there's
there are over seven billion people in
the world
for those billion not really online
not really engaging
um so
the revenue that just facebook alone is
making
it's crazy money i mean i don't know how
else to say it
um not to mention amazon google
apple all these other people you know
making money um what if
what if there were a central
or decentralized program
by which we didn't
utilize or or be able to harness
not just a little over two billion
people
but close to that seven billion people
that exist
you we have to factor that in because
it's not
it's not there and i think an
overwhelming
incentive for making that happen
is using um
the thing the only thing that comes to
mind is using game
a principles so
um you know people
want to make an income or want to make
an income beyond what they're making
and and that's an incentive in itself
regardless of how much it is
now um it would grow over
time i i would imagine so
especially the more people that are on
the system
so um yeah yeah i uh
i would factor in there are a lot of
unknowns that would factor in once
uh a decentralized system for the people
and lobby for the people on a political
scale because that's important too
having that collective power to
translate into economic power would be
extremely important in making sure that
all this happens that's why it kind of
has to go hand in hand
but accounting wise you're spending the
money like
if we're collecting it and distributing
it to the data holders
we don't also have a pool of money to
lobby with we don't also have a pool of
money
to to do those things unless we're
re-putting it into a pool and asking
people to
put it exactly exactly because that's an
extremely important part
of building
a platform like this
um and and the distinction between
because it's for for game b players
um separating the game a from the game b
um as an as an entity or as a
corporation is important
um but
i kind of want to be a devil's advocate
in in
in talking about that
um you can
create a game a organization
with gay bee principles
basically a game a uh corporation
let's say for instance um
a google that not only says
do no harm in the beginning but make
sure
that the organization is structured
to be interdependent and interconnected
for people by the people you know
um you have to start
off like this you can't start off as
um the way it's usually done
in in yeah and i know you know
uh when corporations or tech companies
go to um angel investors or investors
period um you're starting down the game
a road that
there is no coming back and that's what
that's what got google basically into
trouble eventually i mean they were
they they came to a point where things
were getting tight
and they had to figure out a way to
maintain the investor
share that they that they had acquired
you know they
they didn't want to fail so they can
they did what any gaming company would
do to
to maintain and boom
they became the most successful company
and you know one of the most successful
companies in the world
but at the expense of us
so i think we both have a similar vision
of like
eventually the people owning
our versions of amazon google facebook
the things that we use that are our data
the people should own them
taking theirs doesn't make sense we'll
probably end up recreating our own
but how to get enough people on board to
do that your
path is through data right that we get
the people on that
so my question is um because i wrote
here i'm like
i don't use amazon because of data i
don't use facebook or google because of
data i'm there to buy something on
amazon to connect with my friends on
facebook to find information on google
so the regular everyday person isn't
going to switch over
until they understand their own
information and they have that as a
powerful thing
or when the ubi gets to be a big enough
number 20 bucks might be a big enough
number if i'm not putting anything in
right exactly to entice me over
but then you have google facebook and
them also being like oh wait you're
gonna leave for 20 bucks we'll pay you
40 bucks and they already have the money
they already have that
that there and so how do you get to the
individual
who's in it for their own good because
we're all in it for our own good
to switch over to something that's also
beneficial to their collective good
which is still in it for their own good
um but they can't necessarily see that
collectiveness
in a game a world where like right i'm
on amazon because it's cheap and
convenient they have all the [ __ ] like
where else am i gonna go your thing has
five items or whatever the
that there's yeah how do you how do you
account for that how do you get the
people
okay i'm not sure if you're familiar
with okay let me let me start here
i just i just wrote this down within the
past couple of days
we happen makes more sense the more we
keep in mind the following pillars
that work independently together okay if
you don't mind do me a favor
and write down these five pillars which
are
what i call five pillars of power
dynamics
number one is physical power
number two is collective power
number three is digital power
number four is political power
number five is economic power
all right now all of these powers
and i can go into more detail on each
one and
specifically what each one means as we
go along
but just keep in mind that each one of
those powers are
symbiotic to everything we're talking
about and they have to
work hand-in-hand they will work hand in
hand when building
a company that you're asking about
all right i'm not sure if you're
familiar with
peter thiel do you know who peter thiel
is
i'm not great with names okay okay i
don't think so
yeah yeah no problem no problem i know i
i know you know who elon musk
is elon musk well peter thiel
and elon musk were part of what what
they call the
paypal mafia they created paypal
all right but peter thiel has become
famous
now for his book called zero to one
now you can sum up his whole book
and basically a few sentences
zero to one basically means
uh a unique company so unique that it's
a monopoly basically like
google right
he advocates that if you're going to
build a company
don't waste your time with creating
anything else other than a zero to one
company
something that that would eventually
become a monopoly
well um
okay let's see advocated for zero to one
all right yeah if you're not reading
zero
oh okay um um let's see establish
business with and
basically waste your time okay
ask yourself
oh this is another thing he he asked he
says
ask yourself this and this is what
a zero to one company should try to
strive for um
i guess your ethos is what do you
believe that others would disagree with
you on
all right and an example
um of that is and i think the premise
behind that is the more
opposition you get against your opinion
the more likely
a zero to one concept
you know is is created you know
uh and an example i come up with
that i can think of is
billionaires
will be integral to creating
a game b world in the future
okay i didn't say what type of
billionaire
i didn't say the billionaires living
today i just said
billionaires but um
i could also add in that there will be a
lot more people other than billionaires
that'll contribute to
a game b world and making the game b
world that we envision
you know closer to a
utopian type style world even though i
don't believe that they'll ever be a
utopian
uh we won't ever see that in our
lifetime but
the closer we get to that um
but yeah i most people
one of my last conversations i had with
a tech guy
as soon as i told them that that
billionaires would
basically be important in making this
world
yeah he was like nah and i don't see it
which is you know also enough on that
one yeah yeah that doesn't mean i don't
see
that yeah yeah yeah yeah but but i i say
that to
um because i wanted to especially with
game b players um
give them an example of an idea that
they can't
envision in their in their
for themselves seeing that that's a
possibility because
i think we live too close to a game b
existence now where billionaires could
care less
about creating a game b world
i mean it's more so about perpetuating
because i think that that's not true i
think people like elon musk and bill
gates
are are living into their whatever their
version of game b
future is the issue is when you have
that much
power and money associated with one
person you're effectively creating your
utopia which is very different
than billions of people working towards
their individual utopians because you
have so much money in power
i don't think they can create game b
because game a works for them
and they can't see where it's broken and
they're working towards their futures
and they have way too much money in
power
so they're just gonna make it happen as
opposed to allowing it to happen
i don't think that's what and then i
think just being a billionaire itself
you had to accrue so much
off of human suffering that there's also
like the
not necessarily the karma with the money
but like there's a certain amount of
like
you're a little bit of a sociopath if
you're a billionaire
so are you real like even if you want to
do good you can't really quite see the
good
exactly you wouldn't have gotten
billionaire status yeah no no
and i understand and that it makes total
sense
in a game in a game a world you know
without and i love i love the
conversation you had especially the
first conversation you had
with jordan jordan hall
where he talked about and i wrote it
down and
acquiring an embodied wisdom
this is extremely difficult to do for
most people you have to
spend a lot of introspective time with
yourself
understand yourself know how to separate
yourself from the world and what's been
taught to you and all these
conditions that that we are now
um i think that has made us all damaged
basically
until you really dig deep into
who you are you really can't get to
an understanding by which we're talking
about
where a billionaire could
acquire that type of those type of
resources
but yet and still put them back into the
community or have his
objectives not only be
individual or or
or or self-attaining but also
collective giving just as much i mean
so it's extremely hard to to see
that connection within a game a
mentality or a game a world
i mean because it you we don't we
haven't seen it i mean like you said
these billionaires are making or
creating projects on their own basically
they aren't including all of us in it
not at all there's still it's still a
corporation that they still control
you know which is to me the one way
billionaires could create game b
but i don't think any of them will and
this is where i will absolutely
eat my words if it ever happens which is
if bill gates and elon musk put money
into a pool
where we voted on it that's a different
story but they
they think their vision is the utopian
so they're not going to release that to
the people who are like the unclean un
un educated masses right right they know
what they need to do for their health
bill gates we're not taking your vaccine
because we don't trust you you earned
money with a shitty shitty product
that had a monopoly as good as your
intentions might be they're your
intentions whereas if
we if he put it into a pool and said
okay let's collectively decide what a
vaccine looks like are we this or that
that's a different story but i don't one
of them might one of them might come to
that realization and be like oh
that's what's broken about it but yeah
but see that's the thing one billionaire
wouldn't wouldn't do it one billionaire
coming to that realization
is not enough you know there has to be
going back to to the point i made before
um
there has to be a corporation built
on gay may essentially as
gay may but with gay bee principles
whose intentions whose collective
intentions
are to create the resources necessary
to build a game b world um i mean this
is
are you saying so i'm both obsessed with
cooperatives um and currently mlms
that's a whole other story
yeah yeah yeah cooperatives are um
very like are you saying that you're
starting like a game a corporation
meaning it's not a cooperative it's
working like google it's working like
that but
is it transparent is it democratic is it
actually owned by the people from day
one
or what is it what what do you when you
say game a what do you mean
yeah yeah i get gay may in the sense
that
you have to
um be just as competitive
as a google as an amazon as a facebook
if you want to if you want to play in
that world
all right um
so so yeah uh it can
it could be done and to go back to
the zero to one concept
the one thing that facebook google
amazon
will not give up
is is their right to our data or their
their what they see is their right to
make
billions if not trillions of dollars off
of us
they they're not going to give that up
all right the zero to one concept that
i'm thinking about that
would be not only as competitive
but would destroy their whole business
model
is to start off as a game a company
but with game b principles by which
everyone was included on a decentralized
platform everyone had a
a stake in receiving not only receiving
from advertising and all the other ways
you can make money off your data you
know is like i say there's multiple ways
but also giving back
giving back um
when you guys had the discussion about
salary recently
and there's a few things i wanted to
discuss about
about the discussion um
and and i actually oh gosh i wrote
something down earlier
that i was listening to jordan peterson
earlier this morning and and he said
we shouldn't
we shouldn't we shouldn't have to carry
or we shouldn't be worried about
carrying something that
it's not our business to carry some i'm
paraphrasing
you know something like this when
as a group
[Music]
we aren't um
because it's i think it would take in
order to answer these questions
it would take a highly diverse group of
people
of different cultures
different races um i mean
of all different types in order to
understand
why someone would want a ferrari
as opposed to you know just wanting a
you know a small
mini cooper or whatever you know
something cheap
you know you have to speak to these
people
to really get to the gist of why they
want these
things and
to i well it's my opinion
but to structure a game b
uh organization or company
trying to uh or answer these questions
for for other people
is basically placing a barrier
to the connections that you should be
making with the people that you want to
bring in
like and i think you made that
connection during the discussion
you're you're basically saying that you
don't want to
alienate some people
who may want a ferrari you know or may
want to make
x amount of dollars because they want
the big house you know
fine that's great within um
a game a organization with game b
principles
sure you're able to do that because we
know
that regardless of you're going to make
what you're what you're
earned or what you should earn but also
give back
after a certain like let's say um
you could place i'm i'm just riffing
here but
after a certain amount after the hundred
thousand dollars
you after you've reached that plateau it
wouldn't stop
but you're
contractually obligated to give 20
back into either the company or to the
uh community i mean and this is for
everyone
regardless of uh and you know like i say
after you've reached a certain
point where your
your livelihood is taken care of you
choose okay
at this point at 60 000 i'm good
anything i make over that goes back into
the corporation or
the percentage of it goes back into the
corporation meaning
you still will build on your income
but you also know that
what you're contributing is going
back into the community one way or the
other
okay so that's just one way of
of putting it but like i say in order to
get to those answers
you have to have like i say the
i i speak from only experience the black
community
latino community uh asian community all
these people have different values and
opinions about why they want the things
that they want
and and
i have to be honest some a lot of it is
valid
regardless of whether we think oh why
would you need a hundred thousand dollar
car
you know it doesn't make sense so why
would you need a million dollar car it
doesn't make sense
you know doesn't make sense to to us at
the time but
for somebody who can afford it for
whatever reason
you know conditionally speaking they've
made it up in their mind that i need
that million dollar car
who
who in the world is is to judge me for
wanting that car if i can afford it
especially in a game a world
so it's like you're always gonna fight
that
if if if if that's something that you
kind of
include into a game b company and
it's always something a game a company
could take advantage of
but my so as a consumer
or a user or a member
why am i choosing if i'm not game b
right i am the ferrari person i am the
like
what why am i choosing we appen
instead of google or facebook
or like from this other question
actually i'd rather ask another question
zero to one where you talked about
basically creating something that's a
monopoly right
i have the same vision of i'm like right
if we're working together like
amazon and facebook and google can't
compete with us if we're working
together
um since coming into the game b space
and being around i'm not unique in that
and neither are you and so we're already
not a monopoly
like there's already a ton of us now we
have the incentive that we're also
getting b
and therefore my competition isn't my
competition
it's like right eventually one of us is
going to get it right and then therefore
that one does become the monopoly so i
like
like but i don't know if the other
groups
are feel the same way right so therefore
i know right now no one's coming on
board with it and everyone's like oh
great i can scrap mine and go with yours
then
but that's good later on i think it'll
be more obvious which one is the big one
but we're still gonna have that
bifurcation like that
broken up-ness and that hurts our data
that hurts our community that hurts all
of that
decentralization takes part of that on
because you can kind of use the same
stuff
on in different places yeah but then you
don't have a monopoly
holochain has the monopoly right or like
that
that level of absolute levels yeah
but no i i i see i see the premise of
your question i understand um
that's why let's get away from the tech
side
of what we're talking about now and go
to the social side
because there's there's both
um i i currently now have i'm going and
my my mom started it
um a website called linucol richardson
which is basically my cousin
and and my artwork that we're selling
the prints um but
my idea was to say no let's not just
sell our
art let's let's start representing
artists from around the world not only
representing artists from around the
world but
create a collective with the with the
people
because i know artists that have already
joined us who would like to create
collectives that
or just not this where you just don't
show digitally
online but you show you know when
whatever country
um one of the members is at you can
show at a place that they can pretty
much
uh organize themselves and then everyone
within the organization
can join in to show their their work
wherever that's at or send it
so it's all connected i say all that to
say that
i'm i'm using the passion because i'm
i'm an artist
of wanting to not only create art but
show it
right um that's a passion that's not
going away it's gonna be something
that's
created long after um
most [ __ ] jobs are long gone
creativity is gonna be there so this is
the lenicum richardson concept is
basically
grassroots starting um that collective
for artists just primarily for that
you know that's that's their goal that's
their passion
as for them
we when talking to developers about we
happen
we had to we we couldn't make okay uh
the central uh feature of we happen
is connecting your want or offering
to others looking for that information
okay
so if you're looking for a and and
and also creating a a physical search
something that doesn't really exist yet
so say for instance you have a favorite
towel or favorite chair that you
that you'd like to find um
whether in your location or around the
world
this would be a tool by which you could
specifically find what you're looking
for whether that be
a physical object an idea
or whatever it is whatever you're
looking for um
developers said well you you can't make
it too broad you can't
you know you have to focus on basically
one
in order to get do this thing right
focus on one area and at first i thought
okay
events events are large enough is a
large enough
um market by which we could you know if
people are looking
for um you're you're like i'm in a rat
in hip-hop music so
what if i want to know all the hip-hop
con
[Music]
concerts that are going on in my area i
wouldn't miss them if
i say i'm the data is mine
i know the data is mine and i'm sharing
it with this mediator
who's making sure that
all the rat not just rap concerts but
rap events within your area with your
favorite artists
you know about you know okay
so this in this sense this
this is something that doesn't really
exist yet
and and and because
it's customized doesn't exist yet
however i know two to three people who
are working on something similar
and all you know what i mean and this is
the issue with all of the tech projects
is all of them have a very powerful
kernel
yeah and there's a handful of people in
game b working on them
and and so it's it's that monopoly
versus
like yes it's great because one of them
will be the successful one
but then our umbrella ones right that
like we have been together in tech
there's a few other
are like oh no right we're gonna have
ours and we're gonna have no you're not
no we're not because someone else will
already have created it and
then it's where they want to go right
it's like yes if you have a collective
of people
if it's not you know and i know we both
share this vision i think like it's not
george's collective jubilees collective
it's like humanity's collective
exactly and therefore there's a point
where like right if we the more
it's ours the more we're willing to put
our our information
our everything into that and at the same
time
like creating something and then having
to put pieces in
versus creating it together from the
base up is very different
like uh what is the etsy right etsy
is for artists artists use it to sell
their stuff around the world
but it's not owned by the artists it's
not designed for the artists
and so if a bunch of artists on etsy got
together and we're like
what why are we getting some of our
money here why is this and created one
themselves
that's different but george creating one
and then inviting them is
different than them creating it together
and that is that is the piece i've been
working on and not over the last year
but like emerged over the last year
of like okay all of these people thank
god other people have the tech
[ __ ] going on so yeah although i still
am like oh i have a project like i have
a political project i have a science
project i have this i have that i've
solved all the world's problems in my
bedroom
don't worry about that but there's
there's a part of me that my ego gets
hurt when i meet someone else is doing
working in the same space right it's
like oh
no it's my i get to save the world no
but that's okay
yeah no absolutely because it's playing
with that and it's it's also um
i did have a question about this game a
corporation and then game b
and unfortunately i just wrote down game
a versus game b and i didn't actually
think
what is that yeah that's my question i
don't remember
get on it well come back to me yeah yeah
yeah that's the
you know i i live i live in the flow
so if if it was important
if it was an important question for you
then it'll come back to you or it'll
come back in
another form later um
but yeah uh i
i think i not only do i think but i
i know that
these questions that we have will be
answered
once enough people are co-creating
our co-create whatever project that is
and if there's multiple
projects like jeremy lanier says um
there's going to be multiple myths in
which which will be good
there'll be multiple collectives by
which you can opt in or opt
out which best suits your lifestyle you
know
so i don't think
a distinction will be made
as to which is the best
company or organization um people will
naturally
try out your organization whichever that
is
and naturally be compelled to stay
and feel connected to that
as opposed to something else if they
don't then they move on to something
that they do feel connected to
you know but that's the freedom that we
don't have now
and and the beauty beauty of a mid and a
beauty of starting
with a people-centered
philosophy people-centered
principles people-centered foundation
that no other company really started
there's never really been
a corporation or company solely
created to create a lobby for people
represent
people through the organization that
they're building
and building there's probably some
non-profits
and cooperatives that have definitely
done that but not at the grand scale
global scale exactly the large one
i remembered my question okay okay
so if you're starting a game a
corporation with game b values
versus kind of what together tech is
trying to do which is start a game b
corporation within game a
right start very cooperative so if
you're starting a gaming
corporation that is generally
shareholders investors doing those
things but but doing it in a way that it
can't be co-opted like google i'm
guessing i don't
quite know the ins and outs but either
way if it's about money right if it's
about getting
billionaires made if it's about any of
that not necessarily about that but if
that's part of it
if you lose that corporation you lose it
in game a right which means you lose
money
you lose somewhat relationships but
mainly the money right whatever's
invested
if there's a if there's a competitor and
the competitor wins
even if they're amazing in game b this
entity loses loses its money right or it
amalgamates but like let's just say
there's a winner and a loser
um if it's game b if what we're creating
it's like
we're creating it in the way of like
okay well we are building those
connections building those relationships
and we're doing it in a way where like
it doesn't matter if we fail because one
we're only putting in money or
our time we want to but it also is like
right there is no failure because every
time if there is a failure that data
goes back into that system that
information goes back in those
relationships still maintain or they
don't but like
you know what i mean like there isn't oh
wait i put a million i you told me this
was going to be successful i was going
to be rich this was going to be the
solution to the to the
to the world right but someone else
saved the world so we're still good on
that it's the money part that's the
problem right so if
if together so that that like if it's a
game a corporation you fail in a game a
way
whereas if it's a game b corporation
there is no failure
if that means yeah yeah no no i
understand because i think
i think your discussion
touched a little bit on that um
and and and that's where the disconnect
for explaining this
is it gets difficult
because you can say yeah i want to
create a
game a uh corporation
when actual when in actuality i don't i
don't
i should go back and say no don't really
don't make it a corporation because it's
not
in essence a game a corporation when
you're
not taking on you know and your your
primary
uh resources are not coming from
investors by which they
you know their their motivation
is to make money which most people
coming on
in will will probably have that
motivation but
you can i think what what your brother
brought up too was if you create a
system by which
their incentives early on
before starting this corporation that
says hey
okay you may not make
this certain amount of money but you'll
be will
give you resources to live or have a
living wage
at a certain point i think he said he he
jumped at that opportunity
in a second especially if it were
if the funds for creating that corporate
or i say corporation but company
was solely funded through the people
not through investors um it's a totally
different way
of creating a game a company
even though because it this it's got
some strong game b principles
but i believe if you started off as a a
private company and not go
public um i think you can pretty much
structure that company however you want
you know because you're not restricted
to
the rules and regulations of being a
corporation so
there are a lot of there there are a lot
of things there that i'm not
really an expert on but i i think i
understand enough to know that
yeah corporations once you go down that
road
um you're pretty much locked in you know
but it can be done creating a game a
company can be created
with a collective that understands
that our intent is not to
our first intent is not to make as much
money as possible
so everyone can be rich no our intention
first intention is to be a
representative for you
and everyone else not just within
i i truly believe this just can't be a
national
organization has to be a global
organization in order to
reach the numbers that would be needed
to create the
second phase of we happen and i haven't
talked about the second phase
second phase is basically establishing
an llc
and what that basically is this is an
acronym for
life learning community where by which
it's symbiotic we we happen and as
members
yes people are giving and taking within
this interdependent
system which most of the funds are going
back into the community and building
these llc's
so we can start healing
the underlying problems that have
damaged us from
creating civilization you know the
um the fact that
the elderly are the fastest growing
community
that you know need help
toward the latter ends of the year these
could be facilities by which not only
do they get that housing and and help
and
connection between the younger
generation
and impart that wisdom on
people who are
i i envision an llc as okay you go to
school
wherever you're at for half a day
the other half you go to an llc where
it's all about
what's your hobbies skills interests
talents
and we focus on you what is it that
makes you unique
what is it that you want to do and if
you
want to be an artist sure try and be an
artist if that's not
your thing well there'll be
departments by which you can say oh okay
i'll try fashion design
that may be my thing you know and then
you have those resources
available not only just resources and
experts but also the elderly there
that'll be helping and i mean everyone
helping each other it's basically a
physical
we happen you know just in physical form
but all also uh
it's is funded through the people by the
people through
this global interconnection that's been
built
that's and and people understanding that
from the very beginning
i think is not only that yes this
you can empower yourself through your
data
that's just i mean and if that's all you
want to do is make a small income from
your data fine
but you can go far beyond that
you know depending on
your self-interest or your your wants
your needs your
whatever that is i mean it's not for us
to judge
but come be a part of this community
that's global
interconnected interdependent and not
only that
um i i have to tell people this all the
time too
i'm like um a.i
you know artificial intelligence is is
people are afraid of this
people are afraid of what the the the
possibilities and the and the
unintended consequences of creating an
intelligence that's
exponentially far advanced more than us
but i have to one once i
understood fourth industrial revolution
and and
this concept that we're building
co-creating
i'm like what is the lifeblood of an ai
system
it's our data i mean it's pretty much
useless if it can't have access to
all of the data sets that we
provide but
what if before an ai system is created
the organizations globally to control
your data would be implemented
meaning before a company could use your
data
they need you to consent we'd be setting
the foundation for that happening
as opposed to anyone so i do need to go
pretty soon but i
have three questions that brings up a
whole other question that i was like ah
but it might get
um maybe i'll just give you the question
and then and then we can have a chat
about the other time but one of the
questions i did want to ask before we
went at the end of this video
is how far away is we happen from
happening how many people do you need
and how much money do you need in order
to like get that
in order for a random person to get
value from it from coming on day one
right that they're like able to use it
not just see the vision
um so if you want to answer that and
then i'll think about what that other
question is yeah
yeah yeah i'll be i'll be totally honest
with you and every time i
ask that same question of myself
there's going to be a great period by
which um
it's going to um
i don't know if you're familiar with the
diffusion of innovation
um this is a a tech concept by which or
when you
when you start a new idea um
you put it out into the world um
you're going to get those those first
few people those people that first come
on
that are going to understand the vision
be with you be totally there i mean and
i think
jordan peterson in one of your
discussions
talked about um
finding your tribe that first thousand
jordan hall right
i didn't talk to jordan oh i'm sorry
sorry jordan hall yeah
yeah yeah i'm sorry i'm getting the
names mixed up but yeah jordan hall
finding your first thousand um
that are truly passionate and understand
the vision on what you're doing
um going out and finding 10 people
you know to bring in and then building
that tribe
on that in order to get i i truly feel
like
doing that along along with um
crowds funding through kickstarter or
something like that
would not to mention the the social
groups the artists
from linda richardson the social
activists
that we totally transformed because that
i
forgot to tell you about we have been
linking it to
so a social group are all of the
protesters that are out now
i mean millions around the world
what do you do other than just leave the
protest
afterwards they could harness
that people power through a central
platform that's decentralized and had
their i mean
if it were there you know as opposed to
just
breaking up and not much happening after
after the protest
so yeah you wouldn't up until these
protests the like current
black lives matter protests that are
having an actual impact there's defund
the police
there's things going on i'm like why are
we out marching in the street has zero
impact
there's not we need to be creating the
platforms this time i'm like okay there
are changes that are happening
but we also need the platforms because
it's not that effective to have millions
of people marching in the street
instead of millions of people putting in
15 minutes a day like
doing actual [ __ ] that's going to save
the world but like yeah
that using what they're already doing
and giving them other tools
is is powerful i remember my other
question which is my other issue with
data
right is that one my big issue is that i
don't think there's enough money there
to pay a ub
a ubi or udi um but you're saying that
there possibly is and i don't i don't so
that's that's yeah
yeah is that like i said our data is
cheap and so therefore i don't think
there's enough for a udi but i'm happy
to be proven wrong on that and
um the other piece is that our data is
also priceless
and can't like so if i have to give an
okay every time my data is used
it's actually gonna hurt what can come
out of that system
so if i can give like but i don't want
my data being used by google and
facebook and amazon but i do want it to
be used by millions of people all over
the world who are like hey i got 15
minutes to work on cancer
i'd like to have access to this data and
so there's that
part like if it's behind a paywall and
i'm the user and i need to get paid for
it so i'm like
am i gonna let facebook use my data or
i'm gonna get the let the cancer
researchers well facebook gave me 50
cents so if you're not going to give me
50 cents then no
but the cancer research needs billions
or millions of people doing it right so
you need
millions of people to access your data
not one person
and so how do you how do you tap into
the priceless part of data which is what
i'm more interested in anyway i want to
coordinate with my neighbors i want to
do all of all of that
yeah yeah i i i truly believe this would
um like i say this can't be answered
until you have
the network effect of having that many
people on the platform
who and and because once you do you're
going to get a
you know opinions that are infinite when
it comes to
how and who to share that data with
who to give consent to that data
but there will be a tipping point by
which i truly feel
you you get enough people saying oh i
want to make an
income from my data why not whether it
be fifty dollars a hundred dollars a
week whatever it is
sure i'll do it um i think there's a
network effect that'll happen that more
and more people
will join and of course more and more
people will be
saying oh yeah okay
i just want to make an income for myself
i could care less about any social
uh act
or event or companies out there trying
to do good in the world
who cares but the more people you get on
that platform the more
they will but not only do we we'll
will we be able to pinpoint those people
who are more
game b or just who just care about the
environment or care about the planet or
care about
whatever issue is out there and want to
contribute to that
then they'll be connected you know but
until that
infrastructure is there there is no way
of
really making that happen it has to
start somewhere
and it's going to be incremental
initially but i think
like i say once network effects happens
and millions of people are on it
it's not going to be that far away i
think before
there'll be enough resources of people
making enough money
for their data to the majority of people
in the world will be like
you'll be
basically not um working within your own
self-interest not to be on a platform
like that is do you want to does that
make sense
yeah no no i more talk about people
being on the platform
but not willing to share their data
right because they're getting paid in
one place and not another place
like what you said about
environmentalism and that like like i i
get that and i can find people to work
on things with
but for let's say i want to try a new
restaurant but i don't know which one
um there'll be enough people in the
system that have my same taste palette
that that's probably fine but for cancer
research
you actually need everyone's data
not just the people who care about
cancer's data right because that wrecks
it that wrecks it scientifically if you
only have the people who are like wait
yeah i had a cousin who died of it yes
put me in there put me in there put me
in there
if it's an opt-in system then it breaks
the research now that doesn't mean it
has to be perfect research but if you're
basing it because you're going to do
actual studies after usually
but like even even the preliminary stuff
it's going to be
too broken because it's going to be like
oh it's only the social justice warriors
who have their data in the system
so we know cancer treatment for you know
what i mean or like environmentalists or
like those are the people we understand
but like all of the
now part of it is that um because of how
demographics work
if there's a demographic that's less
willing to share their data they're
actually the demographic that is most
hurt
so if you have what i mean white men
born on a tuesday not sharing their data
then it's going to be white men
born on a tuesday who aren't in this
system and therefore
they're they're going to be the ones who
are most hurt by that but
that financial incentive to sell my data
one place i think
hurts the data pool is just like a
hypothesis
that it it creates the wrong incentive
it creates a game a incentive
um of our data but people are so used to
that that i get it but at the same time
it's like that it's already kind of
broken before you get to like
no this is going to be a data pool of
volunteer data right that we can you you
can keep it and you can use it but like
there is a greater good
if you're also selling it then there's
like a
but then is someone going to get in
sneak into and get
my data for free because google's going
to say they're working on cancer
you know like are all those like yeah
how do you
how do you make it priceless when it's
cheap and help you
yeah yeah that's that's what i think now
yeah yeah i'm saying i'm we're trying
we're
we're making it happen we're right here
but the thing is um
i i i truly believe like i say um
you have to think of all of these
pillars working
hand in hand working together um
in order to create the incentive that
people understand enough to know huh
okay it is within my self-interest
to share my data regardless of whether i
get anything back or not
i mean it's part of messaging there too
and part of selling that message and
making sure that people understand
that you know we're collective here
and if we aren't working together then
um
we're not making the world better for
your family and your children's children
in the future um i
i truly believe though that like like
you say the incentive
the the monetary incentive um
could be problematic but i i i think
it's it's
i think it could be a trojan horse for
lack of a better word
to a better system once we get enough
people
on board once we get it cause right now
everybody's willy-nilly doing their own
thing
there's too many silos and there's no
messaging at all
and so that's part of the so sorry
there's a new thought coming through
like game a is is somewhat funding this
right
you udi is coming from the for-profit
capitalist corporations right to put
into the system
yeah so even if we really want to create
game b
we really want to create in my version
of moneyless society and resource-based
economy those kind of things but that
doesn't mean that's where we're ending
up that's just my version of it
um that there comes a point where
they're
like we're hurting those corporations so
much they can't put money
in and yet there's like we're not
creating the infrastructure to take it
over so basing it
like making your bread and butter the
game a world
lit sticks you to game a because why
like if i'm making my ubi udi right i'm
paying my rent i'm putting food on the
table
because these for-profit corporations
are using my data
like they're losing money so they're
going to be less likely like i don't
understand how you keep game a going in
order to fund that
while dismantling it well yeah see i
think
yeah i think it goes hand in hand when
they're losing money
i i mean it's just my
shortwave thinking they're losing money
because more people
see the benefits of joining a
a gay may with game b principles that
will eventually that are
paying them a udi over time that's
growing
and more people are seeing that leaving
the because
it's it's not so much and
we happen to also change the way uh
ad advertisement would be run
um to give you an example the the more
people who trust
in the fact that oh i'm receiving a udi
i'm more likely to share my data
but share my data with companies
who are in line with what i want so
we're making that
relationship basically because
early on you know shortly after the guy
in guatemala
offered me the ten thousand dollars the
developer told me george
you're missing the point of what you're
what you're creating
it's not just about the advertising
dollars it's about the businesses
who want to connect to those people out
there
who are specifically looking for their
business service
or product and making that relationship
one-on-one
you know i mean absolutely but pain for
that relationship
breaks that very thing because as a user
i want to know what's going to have my
biggest values in alignment right i want
to know what's going to be cheapest
what's going to be easiest what's going
to be fastest what's going to not hurt
the planet what's going to all those
things together
so if as a business you have to pay to
get me
then that's then why am i why i'm not
going to go with the local mom and pop
because they're not going to know
they're not going to node advertise to
me if it's free
then i'm going to get if it's free for
all of them then i'm going to get the
best one for me but if they have to pay
for that relationship it's going to be
the people who are most gay may the
people with the most money
unless it's the unless like i don't know
how you spur that
circle like how you if it's most who i'm
who's gonna benefit me the most isn't
necessarily who's gonna pay the most
right or going to
no no yeah
from from what i'm envisioning just
initially speaking it
the relationship won't be based on how
much you're getting paid
through someone else the mediator is
or we have been as an info
media is your representative
so um it's just making sure that
your needs whatever they are are taken
care of
when it comes to your data you know do
you do you want to be in a pool of
people
where your data is on the stock market
sure
do that do you want to have a
be in a pool of people where your data
is uh
shared for free or so to businesses
within your community
sure do that i mean but that's
that's the responsibility of your mid
and if your
your mid is not doing
specifically what your values are and
holding on
to what you like as far as either in udi
or anything else then
you're more than happy to to go to
another
uh representative that will take care of
those needs for you
um and and there may be one that
totally uh
not incentivized by money at all i i
mean i i can't envision
that right now but there could possibly
be one in the future
where everyone comes together pulls
their money and has something closer to
your idea where you pull in
what is it 25 and
you know the the organization is built
off of that
i mean who knows but um
but i think my big thing is to
um create something that's actionable
right now start failing fast
with as many people as possible getting
as many
opinions and and and hands-on debt
to start the transition
from the that because i think that's my
largest motivation is
the transition of power from the one
percent to the 99
however we can get that done let's do it
because otherwise the one percent
is eating eating our lunch i mean it's
it's just
this i mean there's nothing else to be
said about it
and they could care less about changing
it yeah
as i'm saying i created i don't know if
someone else also created it so
yeah but is uh like this idea that we
need to eat the rich right that's like
okay well
we'll like guillotines let's go kill
them like we don't need to eat them we
just have to stop feeding them
that's it like besos doesn't have money
because we nicely gave it to him he has
money because we chose to shop on amazon
right if we give people an alternative
to amazon that's actually an alternative
that gets you your goods gets you your
values
no one's choosing amazon like really
who's going to choose it
nobody so it's not that hard to create
it's that if there's a thousand of them
they already are right that's what
amazon has that this other one doesn't
and so
there's something so we've been talking
for uh
only an hour and a half i feel like it's
fun oh we had a little bit beforehand i
was like this is almost the time we were
going to beat for
we got to meet earlier which is nice
again more time to chat
um yeah i would love to at some point
sit down and have you break my idea
i didn't i don't feel like i broke yours
but that's always what i'm like no no no
no no especially before
before game b where where people are
like like
oh do you want creative critique i'm
like that's all i want i'm like this is
my obsession if you can break it for me
by all means break it for me now it's
it's okay because it's like i know a new
thing's coming and a new thing's coming
and a new thing's coming and right now
i'm obsessed with this mlm structure and
this
i'm literally creating an mlm in from a
space of anti-mlm that will bring
people from game a to game b and create
a product that gets better and better
and so i'm still in the process of
figuring it out but um
in a few weeks when i have that written
down if you want to read through it
read through it might be it might be a
video i don't do writing but i'm trying
i'm trying to do a written document
that explains a little more of what the
product is
because the product is what's going to
bring the people in but then i also want
to um anyway so yeah
we've talked about we have we we happen
and we can talk about the other one
please in any time um send me that
information
so i can look it over and um
we are like mine we're basically
same type of people uh we're obsessed
with what we're doing
so any and like i say i don't do
anything ever stuck in guatemala
so anytime you want to talk i'm here um
i'm open
my time is open to you right day or
night so
yeah day or night that's all
okay my brain only works for a certain
section of the moment yeah like
when i wake up till about noon it's
rather reliable after that it gets
reliable but all right goodbye to
youtube and
or not yeah just youtube not facebook
i'm using together tech